(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-01T09:38:36.230132",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
私と take a step yeah
Take a step with me, yeah...
今宵はバラ色 night
Tonight is a rose-colored night.
夢をのせて踊りましょう
Let's dance upon our dreams,
アローナ！
Alona!
準備はOK？
Are you ready?
まだまだ知って 隠しちゃって 笑顔でアローナ
Still wanting to know more, hiding it with a smile, Alona.
胸のドキドキが止まらないの
The pounding in my chest won't stop,
だからもっともっと
so even more, even more,
強く強く抱きしめてね
hold me tighter and tighter!
アキロゼチャンネル
AkiRose Channel,
いつでも待ってるよ
I'll always be waiting for you.
アローノー！ みんな見えてる？ 聞こえてる？
Alona~! Can everyone see me? Can you hear me?
ホロライブ所属の妖精ハーフエルフ、アキ・ローゼンタールことアキ・ローゼンタールです！
I'm Aki Rosenthal, the half-elf fairy belonging to Hololive!
はろはろはろ～アローナ！
Hallo hallo hallo~ Alona!
ということで、お待たせ新宿カノン...
And so, thank you for waiting...
お待たせしました！今日はアキローゼンタールちゃんのね、1ヶ月遅れの生誕祭3D配信をやっていきたいと思います！
Thank you for the wait! Today, we're going to hold Aki Rosenthal's 3D birthday stream, one month late!
今日はね、アキローゼンタールのこの異世界カフェも、すごく誕生日仕様に飾り付けてもらいました！
Today, my alternate-world cafe has been decorated so wonderfully for my birthday!
今日のね、スクショとかいっぱい呟く物をね、このハッシュタグ、こちらね、日本語で「アキローゼンタール生誕祭2021」と、あと英語で「AkiRoseBirthday2021」と！
Please tweet lots of screenshots and things with these hashtags: in Japanese, "#アキローゼンタール生誕祭2021", and in English, "#AkiRoseBirthday2021"!
こちらダブルづけしてもらえると、アキロゼちゃんも探しやすいので、ぜひいっぱい上げてくださーい！
If you use both together, it'll be easier for AkiRose to find them, so please tweet lots of them!
そして、なんとね、何やら何やら、飾り付けの他にも今プレゼントが届いてきてるんですけど！
And what's more, apart from the decorations, some presents have started arriving!
わぁ、これ、みんなのスーパーチャットというのの、プレゼントがこちらに届いています！ ありがとう！ やった！
Wow, gifts from everyone's super chats have arrived right here! Thank you so much! Yay!
ん？ ん？
Hm? Hm?
なんだこいつ？ なんか、ひっこぬかれたみたいなやつ見えない？ ちょっと…
What is this guy? Doesn't it look like it was pulled right up? Wait...
取れたかな？
Did I get it?
いくよー！
Here we go!
せーの、すっぽーん！
Ready, pop!
ぽーん！
Pop!
出たー！
There it is!
じゃぶじゃぶ？
Jabujabu?
じゃぶじゃぶ、お前！
Jabujabu, you!
ついに体を手に入れたんか！
You finally got a body!
めっちゃ動いてる！
You're moving so much!
じゃぶじゃぶの波動を感じる。
I can feel Jabujabu's aura.
ということで、アキロゼちゃんのミニキャラであるね、こちら、じゃぶじゃぶが、なんと、ツインテールにも出てきたー！
So, Akirose-chan's mini character, Jabujabu, has somehow appeared as twin tails too!
うれしー！
Yay!
さらにですね、あの、ちょっと、こんなこともできるようになりました、アキロゼちゃんといえばね、あの、な、
And also, um, I can now do something like this. Speaking of Akirose-chan, um,
これね、浮いてるやつ。
This thing that floats.
せーの、どーん！
Ready, boom!
きたー！この浮いてるツインテールが、ま、取り外し可能になりました。見て！
It's here! These floating twin tails can now be removed, you see? Look!
このさ、ショートバージョンのアキローズアミールとか初めてじゃない？
Isn't this the first time seeing Aki Rose's short version Amiel or something?
これも好き？
Do you like this too?
こんなこともできる。ぴょんぴょん！
I can even do this. Boing boing!
あ、すみませんでした。失礼しました。
Ah, I'm sorry. Excuse me.
ということでね、今日は、いよいよ、お誕生日なので、飲み食いしちゃってもいいですか？
So today, since it's finally my birthday, is it okay if I eat and drink a lot?
よいしょー！ビール召喚！きたー！
Heave-ho! Beer summon! There it is!
これでみんな乾杯して、始めっていきましょう！
Let's all toast with this and get started!
それでは、アキロゼ生誕祭、アキロゼバースデー！チューゼロチューワン！
So then, Akirose's birthday festival, Akirose Birthday! Q0Q1!
今日もまったりと素敵な時間にいれますように、かんぱーい！ちゅあっ！
May we spend a relaxing and wonderful time today too, cheers! Clink!
もう、最高です！ありがとうございました！ふうー、ということでね、ビールちょっと一端ね、おかせてもらって
It's amazing! Thank you very much! Phew, so anyway, let me put the beer down for a bit
なにやら、なにやら、あ、おかせてもらって、ふうー、なにやら、なにやらね、今日は、宇王海さんが
Something, something, ah, letting me put it down, phew, something, something, today, Uōkai-san
プレゼントを用意してくれたみたいなんたよね。なので、ちょっと、早速なんですけど、最初のコーナーいっちゃいたいと思います。
seems to have prepared a present. So, um, right away, I'd like to go to the first corner.
箱の中身はなんだろなー！
What's inside the box!
イェイイェイイェイイェイイェイ！ということでね、やつの、謎のやつ。
Yay yay yay yay yay! So, that mystery thing.
見覚えがありそうでなさそうでありそうなやつ。お前にね、あのアンポンタンシスターズで一度ここでやったんですけど、メンバー限定の動画で上がってたりとかするんですけど、これを、なにやね、中身を当てたら持って帰ってもいいよって言ってくれたから、いずで当てたいと思います。
Something that looks vaguely familiar yet unfamiliar. You know, Anpontan Sisters did this once before, and it sometimes appears in member-limited videos, but if you guess the contents, you can take it home, so I want to guess it.
じゃあプレゼントをもらえるなんてさ、思ってなかったからさー！ね！みんなもね、あ、みんなは見えるのかな？アキロゼの反応ちょっと楽しんでもらって、いいですか？
I didn't expect to get a present! Right? Everyone too, ah, can everyone see? Could you enjoy Akiroze's reaction a bit?
それでは、うん、いっしょ。なぁ、じゃぶじゃぶ、アキロゼさん当てられると思うこれ？
Well then, yeah. Hey Jabujabu, do you think Akiroze-chan can guess this?
できると思う本当に？ヒントとかくれてもいいんだよ。じゃあちょっとアキロゼちょっと目隠ししますので、いそ、はい！
Do you really think I can? You can give me hints, you know. Well, Akiroze will blindfold herself for a bit, so um, yes!
じゃ準備をよろしくお願いします！はい、分かりました！それでは目閉じてます！
So please prepare! Yes, understood! Now closing my eyes!
どこにあるの？ちょっと1分間のうちに当てないとだめらしい。あ、これ！
Where is it? Apparently I have to guess it within a minute. Ah, this!
はいはいはい！これはもう完全のわ、あ、や、どうかな？ちょっとの、ピーみたいなやつに似てるし、ちょっと歌でも流行ったんじゃない？ふはははふははふはみたいなんじゃないのこれ？このね、特徴なのはこのカーブをしているちょっとね、ひからびた感じの右曲がりになっている下垂。これ決定的ですね！これはもう完全、もう正解でいくしかないな！
Yes yes yes! This is totally, ah, wait, I wonder? It looks kind of like a 'pee' thing, and didn't it become popular in a song? Isn't it like fuhahaha fuhaha fuha? You know, the characteristic thing is that it's curved, kinda dried-up looking, drooping to the right. This is conclusive! This is totally, I have no choice but to go with the correct answer!
どうですか？きたー！ということでじゃあ、目を
How is it? There it is! So then, my eyes...
あけて！
Open it!
開ける前に、これどうしたらいい？
Before I open it, what should I do?
今、まだ目閉じてる状態で答え言いたいと思います。
I'll try guessing the answer with my eyes closed.
箱の中身は……
The contents of the box are...
たっぷリカ！
a bunch of paprika!
きつぁあー！
Yes!
上手ず、めっちゃ喜んでる、嬉しいね、それだけで。
Awesome, I'm so happy, I'm glad just for that.
なるほど、運営さん的には赤いリンゴとは間違えるんじゃないかって。
Management probably thought it looked like a red apple.
そんなね、こんな右肩上がりしてるさ、ヘタがついたリンゴはないんですよね。
There's no apple with a stem curving upwards like this.
まあ、ちなみにプレゼントで赤パプリカってどうしよっかなこれ。
Well, getting red paprika as a present... what should I do?
プレゼントだしね、嬉しい、嬉しいよ、うん、嬉しいです、はいはい。
It's a present so I'm happy, I'm glad, yeah, I am.
じゃあという事で、第2問！いきましょう、じゃあ、嬉しいよ、うんうん、うん、嬉しいよ、うん。
Well then, question number two! Let's go! Yay, I'm glad!
応援よろしくお願いします。
Now for the second item, I'm counting on your support.
1個目パプリカだったし、2個目なんかサプライズ的なちょっとこうびっくりさせちゃうようなだいいいものなのかな。
Since the first was paprika, maybe this is a surprise!
よし、じゃあ、いいですか？
Alright, well, is it ready?
いきます。
Here we go.
えっ、何こと？えっ、まさか！ゲームキューブじゃない！硬い！
Huh, what is this? No way! Not a GameCube! It's hard!
さっきと違う固さがある、あっ、何これ？あっ。
It's harder than before. Huh, what is this?
あっ、これはちょっと、ゴリラの波動を感じる、ゴリラの波動を感じるな、これ。
Ah, I feel a gorilla's aura from this.
まさか、やっぱりそういうこと？うちなる筋肉をめざめさせなければいけない、そういうことなんじゃないから。
No way, is that it? I have to awaken my inner muscle!
わかる、どうかなー。
I see, I wonder...
ちょうど壊したたからなさ、これちょうど欲しかったと思ってた気がする。
Well, I just broke mine recently, so I wanted this!
分かった、分かった、わかりました。
I get it, I get it, I understand now.
これ、これは、この中身は、どぅるるるるるるるるる……握力増強マシンみたいなやつ。
This is... like a grip strength training machine.
握力測定器、ほぼ一緒にしないこんなの！どうしよう！
A grip strength meter! Why would you give me this?!
えっと、あきろでちゃんこれやってみてもいいですか？これはじゃあ、スタートかな？
Um, Akirose-chan, can I try this out? Shall I start?
あっ、じゃあ、ちょっとやってみたいと思います。
Ah, well, I'd like to try it out.
片手、右手ね。いきます、せーの、ふー！がー！がー！
One hand, right hand. Here we go, ready, hhh! Graa!
結果、28.2でした。
The result was 28.2.
いやつかなたんの半分か、くそっ、まだまだ足りないな、鍛え足りなかったじゃん。
Man, that's half... I didn't train enough!
ということで、これはあきろでが頂いて帰りたいと思います。
With that said, Akirose will gladly take this home.
やったあ、でも全部正解ってすごくないね、どうしよう。
Yay! But getting everything right is amazing!
すごいよね、おい、喜んでる、喜んでるー。
It's amazing, she's so happyー.
無機ロゼミを感じたところで、そう！
Having felt that inorganic Rozemi vibe, right!
今日はね、あの、バースデーでミニライブをやっちゃいたいと思うんですけど、その前にアイドル以上に大きいを気合しなくちゃね。
I want to do a mini-live, but I gotta get pumped up first!
ということで、ちょっと待っててね！見ちゃだめだよ。
So everyone, wait just a moment! Don't peek.
じゃじゃーん！でたあ！ということで
Ta-da! There it is! And so,
あきろでちゃんのアイドル衣装、実はね、YouTubeの自分のチャンネルでこうやってアイドル衣装をね、着てお披露目するのが初めてなんだよね。
This is my first time debuting my idol costume on my channel.
あっ、フォロワーも来てくれてありがとう、サンキュー！アイラブユー、フォロワー！うま！
Thanks to the followers who came too, thank you! I love you!
どなたもウェルカムだぞ、どなたい、うま！
Everyone is welcome, everyone is awesome!
見てみて！今日ね、このアイドル衣装みんなに堪能してもらおうかなと。
Look, look! I want everyone to fully enjoy this today.
思って。
I was thinking...
ずっと、ゲストを呼んでね、
about inviting guests, and
ゲストを呼んでたくさんちょっと見てもらおうかなと思ってます。
I thought I'd invite guests and have everyone check it out.
それでは早速ゲストさんの番ですかね？どこかな？
Now then, I wonder whose turn as a guest it is? Where are they?
どこかな？どこかな？
Where could they be? Where could they be?
あき、あきー！あきちゃーん！
Aki, Aki! Aki-chan!
その声は、我らが一期生？
That voice... could it be our 1st gen?
イエス！夏色まつりと夜空メルです！
Yes! Natsuiro Matsuri and Yozora Mel!
えー！まつりちゃん、メルちゃん！おめでとー！
Yay! Matsuri-chan, Mel-chan, happy birthday!
おめでとー！ありがとう！おめでとうだよー！
Happy birthday! Thank you! Congratulations!
かわいいね！かわいいね！
So cute! So cute!
やっとね、アイドル衣装でちょっとこうね見せられるようになったんだよね。素晴らしい！
You're finally able to show off your idol outfit like this. Wonderful!
でも今日はねちょっと2人にもよりね、あのカメラさんをねこう頼ってこういうポーズさせろみたいなところで
And today, I want to ask you two to rely on the camera-san to strike certain poses,
ファンサービスとかしてほしいんですよ。なにそれなるほど。
and do fan service like that. What? I see.
いいんですか？なのであのこのままねちょっとポーズの指定をしてをもらいたいなと思っておもいます。
Is that okay? Yes. So I'd like you to give instructions for poses just like this.
お願いします！オーケーオーケー！
Please! Okay, okay!
じゃあどっちからいきますか？あ、ちょっと待って、どうやら、なんだやらビデオメッセージが届いてるということ、じゃあ先一緒の見てもらうってもいいんですか？
Well, who goes first? Ah, wait, it seems a video message has arrived. Is it okay if we watch it together first?
あ、出てきたよ。あきちゃんのやってほしい動き！
Ah, it's out. Aki-chan's requested movement!
イェーイ！イェーイ！イェーイ！やったあ、やったー！成功綺麗です！
Yay! Yay! Yay! Hooray! Success! That's clean!
てことで、とことん甘噛みですね。白かみでございます。
So, total tongue-twisting. It's Shirakami.
今回あきちゃんにリクエストをしてほしいということで、白かみは動画でリクエストをさせていただきまーす。
For this time, since I want Aki-chan to fulfill a request, Shirakami has submitted a video request!
つまり、あきちゃんにしてほしい動きは……。
In other words, the movement I want Aki-chan to do is...
デデデデデデデデ、サンバ！
Dededededede, Samba!
サンバ！サンバ！ってまつりちゃんのやつじゃない！
Samba! Samba! Isn't that Matsuri-chan's?
生意気な動きはできると思うんですけど、サンバのようなですねキレのある動きができるのかどうかちょっとやってもらおうかなと思います。
I think she can do sassy movements, but I want to see if she can do sharp movements like samba.
今から白神がサンバの楽曲っぽいのを口ずさむので、あきちゃんそれに合わせて踊ってください。行きますよ。
Now Shirakami will hum a samba-like song, so Aki-chan, please dance along to it. Here we go.
せーの！ペペポポペペポポピポポポポポポポポポポポ、サンバ！サンバ！サンバ！サンバ！サンバ！サンバ！
Ready, go! Pepepopo pepepopo pipopopo popopopo popopopo samba! Samba! Samba! Samba! Samba! Samba!
イェーイ！ちゃんとどうかな？ちょっと白髪後でチェックするからな！どうよ？どうよ？
Yay! Did she do it right? Shirakami will check later! How was it? How was it?
カオスだったなー。カオスだね。でもすごいキレキレだったね。
It was total chaos. Total chaos. But it was super sharp!
なんかさ、だって初めてさ、言われたわけじゃん。サンバしてくださいって。
I mean, it's the first time I've been told to "do the samba."
そうでうちのらサンバちょっと開放できたか口づさむにもかかわらずね、やっぱね、すごい対応力が流石のダンスアイドル、アイドル力も上がっているということで、上がってますよ。
Even though I hummed a samba tune, your adaptability is truly that of an idol dancer... your idol power is going up!
よし、じゃあまつりさんとメルちゃんにもちょっと引き続きアキロゼをね、ちょっと盛り上げてもらいたい。お願いします。
Alright, then I'd like Matsuri-san and Mel-chan to continue hyping up AkiRosé. Please.
じゃあ、まつりからいってもいいですか？はい。
Well, can I go first, Matsuri? Yes.
いや、まつりはね、あの結構アイドル衣装後ろ姿見ることもないから、まずスターバ後ろ姿からの、振り返って
Well, Matsuri, since we rarely see the back of your idol outfit, first let's have you start from the back, turn around,
で、カメラさんにちょっと上から撮ってほしいんですよ。あの、上から撮影できるようにちょっと上から撮ってもらって、振り返ってからの、
and have the camera-san shoot from above. Like, shoot from above so you can look down, turn around,
どうしたの？みたいな、で、グイッて近づいてほしいんだって。思います。
and like, "What's wrong?" and get close abruptly. I think.
いいですか？はい。じゃあガチ恋できるような感じで。いいっすね。いいですね。ちょっとじゃあお願いしてもいいですか？じゃあきゅうふりするんで。はい。ガチ恋いさせてください。それではいきますよ。アキロゼのガチ恋ポーズそしてセリフまで。3、2、1、きゅん！
Is that good? Yes. Then make it feel like gachikoi. That's good. That's nice. Can I ask for that? Then I'll count down. Yes. Let us fall hard for you. Here we go. AkiRosé's gachikoi pose and lines. 3, 2, 1, kyun!
どうしたの？
What's wrong?
そんなに見つめられちゃ、恥ずかしいよ。だめ。
Staring at me like that... it's embarrassing. No.
いやめちゃいい、こんなん見てしまうよ。長い、もっとぱっと全て見れるのが本当に可愛い。
Oh, this is great, seeing something like this. It's long, but being able to see everything all at once is really cute.
あ、わかる。ちょっとってなってるの可愛いな。やけどったぜ。
Ah, I know. It's cute how she gets all flustered. I'm burning up.
メル師匠！せっかくの祭り、メル師匠...
Master Mel! Since it's a festival, Master Mel...
あっ待って、メル師匠、祭りじゃん！メルも頑張るよ！
Wait, Master Mel, it's a festival! Mel will do her best too!
オーケー！
Okay!
えっとね、えっとまずしゃがんでもらって
Um, first, could you crouch down?
あっ、メル師匠もしかして前回の去年の誕生日でもなんね、
Ah, Master Mel, by any chance, during last year's birthday...
結構なあの過激なことになってたから、大丈夫だっ？そんなこと...
Things got pretty intense, so are you sure? Something like that...
ちょっとしゃがんでもらって... はい、違います！
Just crouch down... Wait, no!
はい、しゃがんでもらって、カメラさんは、あっ、やっぱりね、上から撮ってもらって
Okay, crouch down, and for the camera, ah, as expected, take it from above.
上からの、はい、ま、ちょっと消しゴム落としたよみたいな感じで
From above, yeah, like dropping an eraser.
あーいいね、消しゴム... お姉さんっぽい、お姉さんっぽいね
Ah, nice, an eraser... Very mature, very mature.
そう、しゃがんでからの、うん、ちょっとこうなんだろうな、手元を胸元に置いてさ
Right, after crouching, um, putting your hands near your chest...
消しゴム落としたよ、っていう感じで、うん、お願いしまーす
Like you dropped an eraser, yeah, please do it like that.
この消しゴム... 君の... 消しゴム落としたよ！はい！
This eraser... Yours... I dropped my eraser! There!
やばい、やばい、消しゴム... なんか中にアキロゼハートって書いてるのばれ...
Oh no, oh no, the eraser... It gives away that 'AkiRose Heart' is written inside...
ほんとに！今消しゴムじゃなくて恋に落ちるわ、これは！... そういう仕込みだったのね！
Seriously! Instead of an eraser, I'm falling in love with you! ...So that was the setup!
たまらんね！たまらんね！それが恋だな！お尻笛とかの...
I can't get enough of this! That's what love is! The butt whistle or...
お尻笛鳴りましたね！... お尻笛鳴りましたね！
The butt whistle blew! ...The butt whistle blew!
いやーありがとう！いやーちょっとアイドル力もさらに上がったと思います！もう可愛すぎます！
Man, thank you! Man, I think my idol power went up even more! It's too cute!
二人とも撮影に協力してくれてありがとう！いや、こちらこそ本当にたくさんありがとうございます、むしろ！
Thank you both for helping with the shoot! No, thank *you* so much instead!
もっともっとポーズ撮らせたかったけど... みんなで実際やりたいですよね、それよね
I wanted to take more poses... But we should actually do it together, right?
まつりはいいかな？アキロゼのを見れれば... いやいやそれはまつりすだが許さないよ！じゃんもやるんだよ、どうなるの？いつかかな？
Is Matsuri fine? As long as I can see AkiRose... No no, Matsurisu won't allow that! Mel's gonna do it too, how will that turn out? Someday?
ということで二人ともまとめね... うん、ありがとう！おめでとうだよ！ありがとう！
So with that, wrapping it up with both of you... Yeah, thank you! Happy birthday! Thank you!
記念の1年にしようね！しようね！ありがとうね！今後も楽しみにしてますよ！歌もダンスも楽しみにしてるから！
Let's make it a memorable year! Thank you! I'm looking forward to the future too! Looking forward to your songs and dancing!
わかった！頑張って... じゃ、またね！
Got it! I'll do my best... Well, see you later!
はーい、はーい、フブキちゃんのね、ビデオメッセージでそして祭りちゃんメルちゃんありがとうございました！
Right, right, thanks to Fubuki's video message, and Matsuri-chan and Mel-chan, thank you very much!
さあ、そしてさらにね、豪華ゲストがまだまだいるっていうことなので読んでみたいと思います！
Now, and furthermore, since there are still more gorgeous guests, I'd like to call them out!
次なる豪華ゲストさんは誰だの？どこだの？いぇーい！
Who could the next gorgeous guest be? Where are they? Yay!
その声は？先輩！先輩！アキロゼ先輩！誕生日おめでとうございます！
That voice is? Senpai! Senpai! AkiRose Senpai! Happy birthday!
おめでとうございます！ココちゃん！かなたんだ！いぇーい！
Happy birthday! Coco-chan! Kanatan! Yay!
来ましたよ！参加しましたね！ありがとう！
We're here! We made it! Thank you!
どうもどうも！今日は、いや、新衣装の... 新衣装じゃないわ、アイドル衣装で
Hello hello! Today, wait, in the new outfit... Not the new outfit, in your idol outfit...
アキロゼ先輩をちょっとスキニーにしてもいいっていう、そういう肩...
Asking if we could make AkiRose Senpai a bit skinny, that kind of shoulder...
どうしようか、ちょっとじゃあこれね、転がったりとかってできますかね？やってみましょう！
What should we do? Can we roll around or something? Let's try it!
お願いします！あ、そのポーズチャレンジ！いいじゃん！
Please! Ah, that pose challenge! Sounds good!
うつぶせかな？あ、仰向けか！いいですね、いいですね、あお... あ、仰向けで、仰向けで
Prone? Ah, supine! That's good, that's good, su... Ah, on your back, on your back.
聖壁出してきたぞ... カメラ、あ、いいで、いいで、カメラ、いいで！アキロゼ先輩、以前だいたい出来てましたけど、今回だめなんですかね？
...Camera, ah, it's fine, fine, camera is fine! AkiRose Senpai, you could usually do this before, but is it no good this time?
ちょっと... カメラさん行ってみます？あ、ダメですか？ダメですか？ダメですか？おっと... 嘘でしょ？
Shall we check the camera? Ah, no good? No good? No good? Whoa... No way?
あ、でもいい！あ、いい！あ、いいですね、いいですね！そのカメラ、あ、いいですね、いいですね！
Ah, but it's good! Ah, good! Ah, that's good, that's good! That camera, ah, good, good!
ちょっと隣に... かなた今隣にいるんですけど、まず気持ち悪いからだ！からだめためちゃめちゃ傾けてる
Right next to... Kanatan is right next to me, but first of all, her body is gross! Her body is tilted way too much!
頑なに... かなた、痛い、痛い、痛い！
Stubbornly... Kanatan, it hurts, it hurts, it hurts!
あ、いいですね！あ、いい、あの曲線が！あ、すてき！かなた、お前がからだ傾げても何も見えねえぞ！
Ah, that's good! Ah, good, that curve! Ah, lovely! Kanatan, even if you tilt your body, nothing is visible!
きもち悪いぞ！あ、足元も映してほしいな、足も！ぱたぱた...
It's gross! Ah, I want you to show my feet too, my feet! Flapping...
かわいくね？足も... やばい、やばい、やばい！うわ、いいですね、最高です、ありがとうございます！
Cute right? My feet too... Oh no, oh no, oh no! Wow, this is great, it's the best, thank you!
もっとインですか？
Is that further in?
もっとせめなくていいですか？
Shouldn't we push it more?
足元もっとせめなくていいの？
Shouldn't we push the foot area more?
ゴリドーザー様のまずちょっ
Goridozer-sama's first, wait...
簡単な、なんていうのかな
It's simple, how should I put it?
マネージャーが許してくれない
The manager won't allow it!
カメラ、もっと
The camera, more...
なんだろな、もっと上に？ もっと下？
What is it, higher? Lower?
いや、つまんないね
No, that's boring.
エムが出ちゃったよ
My submissive side came out!
じゃあちょっとここちゃんそのギリギリのラインでね、そのラインを超えて、超えないぐらいで。
Then Coco-chan, right at that limit line, cross it, but just not quite.
あの、カメラさんの位置を変えてほしいのよ。逆にカメラさんがちょっと猫になって。
Um, I want you to change the camera's position. Conversely, camera-san, become a cat.
あの、なんだろう、あの、突然気を失って、めざめたら、知らない天井、そこに覗き込む、エンジェル！
Um, I wonder, like, suddenly losing consciousness, waking up to an unknown ceiling, and peering down, an angel!
覗き込んでるんですの、私の視界から。
Peering down right into my field of vision!
なんか、カメラさんのその、あ、あの、目覚めましたか？みたいな、こんな感じの、なんというか病院の優しいナースみたいな感じでお願いします！
Sort of like, camera-san, "Did you wake up?", with that gentle hospital nurse vibe, please!
おーい
Hey.
起きた？
Are you awake?
おはよう
Good morning.
ここは、まだ現実だよ
This is still reality.
エンジェルが！
An angel!
やべえ！現実だわ！
Oh no! It's reality!
よかった現実だわ！
Thank goodness it's reality!
最高です！
This is the best!
フジッ子、足がすごいんだけど！
Fujikko, your legs are amazing!
こっちもすごいですね
This side is amazing too.
顔真っ赤っかですからねもう
Your face is bright red already.
肩が気もんだすけど隣で、気もんだすけど完全にあ、変な話してきちまったぜ
My shoulders are tense next to you, but completely—oh, I ended up talking about weird stuff.
いや、でもこれね、やっぱアイドル衣装の良さを分かってるふたりがね、みんなにサービスしてくれたということで
Well, but this, after all, two people who understand the appeal of idol costumes gave everyone fan service!
最高です！
This is the best!
いや、よかった！いや、ありがと駆けつけてくれて
Yeah, that's great! Thank you for rushing over.
ありがとございました
Thank you very much.
また遊んでくださいね
Please play with me again.
ありがとございました！
Thank you very much!
めでとうございました！
Congratulations!
はーい、まったねー！
Bye-bye, see you later!
いやなんかもう
Man, like...
疲れたなあ
I'm so tired...
結構ハイテンションでここまで来たんですが
I came this far with pretty high tension, but...
さあ、このあとは、まだまだ盛り上がってきたいと思いまかね、こからは、バースデーミニライブに行きたいと思います！
Now, after this, we want to get even more hyped, so from here, I want to go to the birthday mini-live!
それは、ライブ会場に、レッツゴー！レッツゴーゴーゴー！
That is, to the live venue, let's go! Let's go go go!
おおー！なんだか美味しそうな匂いがする！
Ooh! It smells so delicious!
おお、すごい！誕生日ケーキじゃない、じょうず！
Ooh, amazing! It's a birthday cake, skillfully made!
わあ、すごいね！今日はね、もう、飲み放題、食べ放題だよ！
Wow, amazing! Today is all-you-can-drink and all-you-can-eat!
早速、食べちゃおっかな！
Let's eat right away!
じゃあ、かんぱーい！
Then, cheers!
おお、すごい！おお、いいね！これもキット食べれるんだろな、ゼロ甘い、よし。
Ooh, amazing! Ooh, nice! Can I eat this kit too? Zero sweetness, okay.
いただきます！ちーず！
Itadakimasu! Cheese!
うわあ！うわあ！見て！もう次野ビールがつがれてるよ！
Whoa! Whoa! Look! The next beer is being poured!
あ、ビールより飲むのが夢なんだ！
Ah, dreaming of drinking beer more than anything!
いやこれ夢なのかな、だんだん現実なんかかんなくなってきたけど
No, is this a dream? It's starting to feel less like reality, but...
ケーキを食べるぞ！誕生日ケーキだからね！
I'm gonna eat cake! Because it's a birthday cake!
いただきます！あむあむ
Itadakimasu! Nom nom.
うんうん、うまいなあ！
Mhm mhm, so delicious!
じょうずも食べる？
Does Chouzu want some too?
おっ、おっ、おお！お、えさお取って、お、ビッグサイズジャビス！あ、かわいいね！
Oh, oh, oh! Oh, taking bait, oh, big-size Jabis! Ah, cute!
いや、でももう一個食べる？
Wait, do you want another one?
おー、じょうず、じょうず、おじょうず！
Oh, Chouzu, Chouzu, good job!
あ、びっくら、ごらん、じょうずのこと、もう一回見たいな
Oh, surprise, look, I want to see Chouzu again!
もう一回、おわあ！じょうず！じょうずの今日、初めて特技が出ちゃったね！江戸版ぐいのごじょうず
Once more, whoa! Chouzu! Chouzu's special skill came out for the first time today! Edo-edition guigui Chouzu!
え、特技ゲットしたじゃん！
Eh, you got a special skill!
じゃあ最後、最後、最後じゃもう一緒に食べよう
Then finally, finally, finally, let's eat together.
じゃあこれを開けて食べよう。もぐもぐ、にゃむにゃむ...
Then let's open this and eat. Nom nom, nyamu nyamu...
最後だ！勝ち！
It's the last! Win!
あんなむにゃむにゃにゃむにゃにゃむにゃにゃむ
Nom nom nom nom...
美味しかった！
It was delicious!
じょうず、もうないよ、もうないよ、もうないよ！いそいそ、じょうずがんばれよ！
Chouzu, there's no more, no more, no more! Iso iso, do your best Chouzu!
あ、ここから本番だからね！酔っ払いちょっとかもしれないけど、行くよ！
Ah, from here is the real deal! Might be a bit drunk, but here we go!
がんばれない行くよ！
Can't do it, going!
今日は遅くなっちゃったけど生誕祭をお祝いしてくれてありがとう！
Even though it's late today, thank you for celebrating my birthday!
ライブパートも盛り上げていくぞー！
Let's get hyped for the live part too!
重ねた手は ぎゅっと離さずに
Our clasped hands, holding on tightly without letting go
行くよ 夢見る空へ
Let's go, to the dreaming sky!
まだ星見上げた ちょっと小さな空
Still looking up at the stars in a slightly small sky,
ここで出会えたのは 数え切れない奇跡
meeting here was an innumerable miracle.
繰り返し一歩が きらめきをつないで
Repeating every step connects the sparkles,
星のような笑顔を導いた
guiding smiles like stars.
いっぱい出会って 女の子が力になる
Meeting so many people gives us girls strength.
Stage by Stage ここでそれぞれ目指すもの
Stage by stage, what each of us aims for here,
それぞれ描くもの それぞれ願い結べ
what each draws, binding each wish.
重ねた手は ぎゅっと離さずに
Our clasped hands, holding on tightly without letting go,
一人違う描き出す ドキドキするトキメキ
each drawing something different, a pounding excitement.
振り返ることなく まっすぐに
Without looking back, straight ahead,
行くよ 夢見る空へ
let's go, to the dreaming sky!
笑い合ったことや 月日隠れないまたね
The times we laughed together, saying see you again across the days,
思い出いっぱいなのにな あともう一歩の日々
even with so many memories, days that are just one more step.
上書きじゃなくて名前つけて
Instead of overwriting, give it a name,
ほどけぬよう まっすぐに
so it won't untie, straight ahead.
One for All 女の子が力になる
One for all, giving us girls strength,
All for One 今日も賑やかすぎるから
all for one, because today is far too lively,
笑顔が留まらない
smiles won't stop.
思いは膨らんでいく
Feelings keep expanding.
重ねた手は ぎゅっと抱きしめた
Our clasped hands, hugging them tight,
一人違う歌声が広がる 歌声を 感じたら
each with different singing voices spreading out, feeling those voices,
まっすぐに 行くよ
straight ahead, let's go
夢見る空へ
to the dreaming sky!
重ねた手は ぎゅっと離さずに
Our clasped hands, holding on tightly without letting go,
一人違う描き出す ドキドキするトキメキ
each drawing something different, a pounding excitement.
出会えたすべてに ありがとう
Thank you for everything we've encountered.
奇跡起こし続けて ずっと ここにいるよ
Continuing to make miracles happen, I'll always be here.
行くよ 夢見る空へ
Let's go, to the dreaming sky!
Thank you!
ふうー！ということで1曲目「夢見る空へ」でした！
Phew! And that was our first song, 'Yumemiru Sora e'!
ありがとうー！
Thank you so much!
いやーこのライブめっちゃ楽しみにしてたんだー！
Man, I was looking forward to this live so much!
ということでじゃあ続いて…
And with that, moving on to...
もしも 私のいのち
If my life
愛し愛されて 抱いて抱かれて
is to love and be loved, to embrace and be embraced,
たとえ 私のいのち
then even if I wager
すべてかけても かまわない
the entirety of my life, I don't mind.
今日もまた夕暮れ
Today again, the evening
西の空を染めて
paints the western sky,
たたずむ私の上に
and standing still above me,
きっと赤い月が出る
a red moon will surely rise.
たちこめる朝もや
The morning mist closing in
東の空を染めて
paints the eastern sky,
今頃あなたの上に
and right about now, above you,
きっと赤い陽が昇る
a red sun is surely rising.
同じ夢 同じ思い 同じ風に吹かれ
The same dream, same thoughts, blown by the same wind,
ただ一つだけ違うのは
the only thing that is different
きっと太陽のめぐり
is surely the circulation of the sun.
もしもこの世の果てに
If at the ends of this world
流れ流されて 揺れて揺られて
I am washed away, drifting and swaying,
たとえこの世の果ても
even at the ends of this world,
あなたがいればそれでいい
if you are there, that is enough.
いつでもこの胸に
Always in this chest
やさしい声が聞こえる
a gentle voice can be heard.
悲しい訳じゃないのに
It's not as though I'm sad,
なぜか涙がこぼれるの
yet somehow tears overflow.
同じ夢 同じ思い 同じ風に吹かれ
The same dream, same thoughts, blown by the same wind,
ただ一つだけ違うのは
the only thing that is different
きっと太陽のめぐり
is surely the circulation of the sun.
あなたのために踊る
I dance for your sake,
思い出の歌に身体預けて
entrusting my body to a song of memories.
あなたのために祈る
I pray for your sake,
明日もきっと晴れるように
that tomorrow too will surely be clear.
同じ夢 同じ思い 同じ風に吹かれ
The same dream, same thoughts, blown by the same wind,
ただ一つだけ違うのは
the only thing that is different
きっと太陽のめぐり
is surely the circulation of the sun.
あなたのために踊る
I dance for your sake,
思い出の歌に身体預けて
entrusting my body to a song of memories.
あなたのために祈る
I pray for your sake,
明日もきっと晴れるように
that tomorrow too will surely be clear.
ラライ ライライ ライライ ライライライ
Lalai, lai lai, lai lai, lai lai lai,
lalai, lai lai, lai lai, lai lai lai,
ラライ ライライ ライライ ライライライ
の、待ってください！
Wait, please wait!
ちょっと ここでね みんなの水が… よいしょ。
Wait, everyone's water is right here... heave-ho.
はぁー、ありがとうございます。
Phew, thank you very much.
やっぱね、この自分の配信でアイドル衣装を着て歌って踊れるのすごい夢だったのですごいめちゃくちゃ楽しいです！
Wearing an idol outfit on my own stream and singing and dancing was such a dream of mine, so I'm having an absolute blast!
ということで、続いたもう一曲いたいと思います。えーこの曲はね、とても、えー気持ちを込めて歌える歌なんじゃないかなと持っています。
With that said, I'd like to do one more song. Um, I think this is a song I can sing with a lot of emotion and feeling.
それでは、聞いてください。ダイヤモンド クレバス。
Now then, please listen to it. Diamond Crevasse.
神様に恋をしていた頃は
When I was in love with God,
こんな別れが来るとは思っていなかったよ
I never thought such a parting would come.
もう二度と触れられないなら
If I can never touch you again,
せめて最後に もう一度抱きしめて欲しかったよ
I just wanted you to hold me tight one last time.
It's long long good-bye...
さようなら さようなら 何回だって
Goodbye, goodbye, over and over again
自分に 無上に 言い聞かせて
I tell myself endlessly
手を振るのは優しさだよね?
That waving my hand is kindness, right?
今強さが欲しい
Now, I want strength.
貴方に出会い STAR輝いて アタシが生まれて
I met you, the star shined, and I was born.
愛せばこそ iがあればこそ
Because I loved, because there was 'i' [love],
希望のない 奇跡を待って どうなるの?
Waiting for a hopeless miracle, what will become of me?
涙に滲む 惑星の瞬きは gone...
The twinkle of planets stained with tears is gone...
忘れないよ 貴方の温もりの
I won't forget your warmth,
その優しさも 全て包んでくれた両手も
Nor your kindness, nor the hands that enveloped me completely.
It's long long good-bye...
さようなら さようなら 愛しい人
Goodbye, goodbye, my beloved.
貴方が いたから 歩いてこれた
I was able to walk this far because you were here.
ひとりなんじゃなかったよね?
I wasn't alone, was I?
今答えが欲しい
Now, I want an answer.
燃える様な流れ星 捕まえて 火を灯して
Catch a burning shooting star and light a fire.
愛していたい 愛されていたい
I want to love, I want to be loved.
冷えたカラダひとつで 世界は どうなるの?
What will become of the world with just a cold body?
張り続けていた 虚勢が溶けていく long for...
The bravest facade I kept up is melting away long for...
どうしてなの? 涙溢れて 止められない
Why is it? Tears overflow and won't stop.
貴方に出会い STAR輝いて アタシが生まれて
I met you, the star shined, and I was born.
愛せばこそ iがあればこそ
Because I loved, because there was 'i',
希望のない 奇跡を待って どうなるの?
Waiting for a hopeless miracle, what will become of me?
涙に滲む 惑星の瞬きは gone...
The twinkle of planets stained with tears is gone...
もし生まれ変わって また巡り会えるなら
If I am reborn and we can meet again,
その時もきっと アタシを見つけ出して
Make sure you find me then as well.
もう二度と離さないで 捕まえていて
Don't ever let go again, hold on tight to me.
ひとりじゃないと 叫んでほしい planet...
Shout out that I'm not alone, planet...
It's long long good-bye...
さようなら さようなら
Goodbye, goodbye,
愛しい人
My beloved.
貴方が いたから 歩いてこれた
I was able to walk this far because you were here.
ひとりなんじゃなかったよね?
I wasn't alone, was I?
今答えが欲しい
Now, I want an answer.
燃える様な流れ星 捕まえて 火を灯して
Catch a burning shooting star and light a fire.
愛していたい 愛されていたい
I want to love, I want to be loved.
冷えたカラダひとつで 世界は どうなるの?
What will become of the world with just a cold body?
張り続けていた 虚勢が溶けていく long for...
The bravest facade I kept up is melting away long for...
どうしてなの? 涙溢れて 止められない
Why is it? Tears overflow and won't stop.
貴方に出会い STAR輝いて アタシが生まれて
I met you, the star shined, and I was born.
愛せばこそ iがあればこそ
Because I loved, because there was 'i',
希望のない 奇跡を待って どうなるの?
Waiting for a hopeless miracle, what will become of me?
涙に滲む 惑星の瞬きは gone...
The twinkle of planets stained with tears is gone...
もし生まれ変わって また巡り会えるなら
If I am reborn and we can meet again,
その時もきっと アタシを見つけ出して
Make sure you find me then as well.
もう二度と離さないで 捕まえていて
Don't ever let go again, hold on tight to me.
新たに出逢いたくて 輝いて 私が生まれて
Wanting to meet someone new, shining, I was born...
愛すればこそ 愛があればこそ
Because I love, because there is love...
希望のない奇跡を巡って どうなるの
Wandering through a hopeless miracle, what will become of us?
涙に滲む 星の瞬きは遠く
The twinkling of stars blurred by tears is far away...
星は巡り変わって また巡り逢いゆくなら
If the stars change and we meet again...
外す鍵もきっと 私を見つけてそして
Surely find me the key to unlock it, and then...
もう二度と離さないで 捕まえてて
Never let go of me again, hold onto me...
一人じゃないと 囁き合って欲しい惑星
Whispering to each other that we're not alone on this planet...
ふう、聴いてくれてありがとうございました。
Whew, thank you so much for listening.
えー、そろそろ配信もね、ラストの方の時間になってきました。
Uh, the stream is getting close to its final stretch now.
ここでアキロゼからロゼ隊のみんなに手紙を書いてきたので、ちょっとせっかくのね、こういう機会なので読んでもいいですか？
So, I wrote a letter from AkiRose to all the Rose-tai. Since it's such a special occasion, is it okay if I read it?
緊張した。緊張したけどうまくできたかな。
I was so nervous. I was nervous, but I wonder if I did a good job.
ロゼ隊へ いつも応援してくれてありがとう！！
To Rose-tai: Thank you always for your support!!
アキロゼここまで続けてこられて、
The reason AkiRose has been able
続けてこられたのは出会ってくれたロゼ隊の力のおかげです。
to keep going this far is thanks to Rose-tai.
何げない言葉に傷ついたり、
There are times I get hurt by casual words,
思い通りにできなくて、高くて大きくて、超えられなさそうな壁にぶつかったり、
when things don't go my way, hitting towering walls that seem impossible to clear,
うまく何もできない自分が本当に情けなくなっちゃうこともよく、まだあります。
and I still often feel truly pathetic for not being able to do anything well.
でも、そんなときに いつも配信とかYouTubeとかコメントでね、
But whenever that happens, in streams, on YouTube, and in comments,
優しい言葉をかけてくれるそして盛り上げてくれるロゼ隊がいます。
Rose-tai always gives me kind words and cheers me on.
配信をすると、みんなと触れ合うと、
When I stream, when I interact with everyone,
アキロゼは元気がでます。
AkiRose gets her energy back.
だから、アキロゼは みんなが疲れた時とか
That's why, when everyone is tired, or...
あとはね、繰り返しの日常に彩りを添えられるような
And also, hoping to be a VTuber who can add color
Vtuberになりたいと思うことができます。
to your repetitive daily lives.
この誕生日を迎えて220歳のぴちぴちエルフになりましたが、
Welcoming this birthday, I became a fresh 220-year-old elf,
まだまだVtuberとして生きるこの生命体としては半人前です。
but as a VTuber and as this life form, I'm still only half-baked.
来年も またこうやってみんなと最高を更新して行けるようなバースデーを 迎えていけるように
Next year too, so we can welcome birthdays where we update our best together—
アキロゼはね、アイドルとしても、ダンスや歌、そして日常の配信とかね、みんなに楽しんでもらえるように そして
AkiRose will work hard as an idol, in dance, song, and daily streams so everyone can enjoy them, and...
アキロゼのことを好きになってよかったって
So that all the Rose-tai can proudly say
胸を張って、ロゼ隊のみんなが言えるように
"I'm so glad I came to love AkiRose!"
だからも、頑張って鍛えたいと思います！
That's why I'm going to work hard and train!
2021年2月(3月)17日にアキ・ローゼンタールでした。
From Aki Rosenthal, February/March 17, 2021.
はい、ありがとうございます。いつも本当にありがとう。
Yes, thank you so much. Always, truly, thank you.
ということでちょっとね、エモい雰囲気になっちゃいましたけど
With that said, things got a little emotional,
こっからはロゼ隊ハッピータイム！堂々の告知！いきたいと思います！
from here on is Rose-tai Happy Time! The big announcement!
グッズの告知だーーー！いえーーーい！
It's merchandise announcement time! Yay!
はい、ということでアキロゼちゃん誕生日記念2021！
Yes, so this is the Aki Rosenthal Birthday Celebration 2021!
こちらグッズの方が発売になります！
Um, the merchandise for this will go on sale!
こちらね、直筆サイン特典にミュージックビデオセットプラスボイス＆グッズ全部セット！
This includes a handwritten signature bonus, music video set, voice, and all-goods set!
なんだかすごいアイテムがいっぱい入っていますが、ちょっと詳しく見ていきましょうか！
It's packed with amazing items, so let's take a closer look!
はい、ということで1つ目！こちら安曇アキタケ先生描き下ろしのアクリルパネルが！あります！
First up! We have an acrylic panel illustrated by Akitake Azumi-sensei!
来たー！こちらさめあんこ先生描き下ろしのラバーコースターとアキロゼちゃんの栓抜き！
Here it is! A rubber coaster illustrated by Sameanko-sensei and an AkiRose bottle opener!
でーたー！今までアキロゼちゃんのグッズマグカップしかなかったんですけど、今回はより楽しめるということで、Cheers! ビールジョッキ作っちゃいましたー！
Ta-da! Until now we only had mugs, but this time we made Cheers! Beer Steins!
はい、こちら全部セットをご購入して下さった方の特典として、マスターの描き下ろし、そしてアキロゼの直筆サイン入りのポストカードと、あとトップテンボイスがセットでついてきまーす！
And as a bonus for getting the all-inclusive set, you get a postcard with a handwritten signature and top ten voice!
そして、なんとまだあります！
And there's still more!
じゃじゃーん！こちら2月17日のブルームライブで初お披露目になりました、アキロゼちゃんのセカンドオリジナル曲「ヒロインオーディション」！これのミュージックビデオ、そしてなんとですね、振り付けのレッスンビデオ！
Ta-da! This is AkiRose's 2nd original song "Heroine Audition" revealed at the Bloom live on February 17th!
待って
Wait,
やってみようかなって思います。
let's try this out!
それでは、アキロゼちゃんの生誕祭2021を締めくくります。
Now, let's wrap up Aki Rosenthal's Birthday Live 2021.
こちらの広いオーディション、
Here is the grand finale!
聞いてください！
Listen carefully!
キミのヒロインは誰…？
Who will be your heroine, I wonder...?
おぼえてる 優しくて キミの言葉にキュンとして
I still remember your gentle words that made my heart skip a beat.
上手く言えない 代わりに微笑みかけてみたの
Though I couldn't say it well, I smiled at you instead.
目が合った気がした それだけで鼓動ハネた
I felt our eyes meet, and that alone made my heart race.
お願い 勘違いじゃありませんようにって
I pray I'm not mistaken!
そっと 心の中で 熱い視線 送ってみたの
Quietly in my heart, I sent you a passionate gaze.
振り向いてって 願っちゃってて
I turned around, wishing and hoping...
ヒロインオーディション エントリーしたら私 選んでくれるかな…？
If I enter the heroine audition, will you choose me...?
マジメな性格 おはようだけで伝わるよ
Your earnest nature shows just in your "good morning."
何気ないつぶやき もしかしてと期待してる
Casual little utterances make me wonder if there's a chance.
眩しい素敵な人ばかりで 自信もなくて
Surrounded by such dazzling, wonderful people, I lack confidence,
それでも本音では 365日 もっと近づきたい
yet deep down I want to be closer to you all year round.
私なりのペースになるけど
I'll take it at my own pace, but...
ヒロインオーディション 勇気を出したら キミは ねぇ、答えてくれるかな…？
If I muster the courage for the heroine audition, will you answer me...?
出会った瞬間ってかなりミラクル このチャンスは赤い糸 ギッと手繰り寄せて 運命にしよう
The moment we met was quite a miracle, this chance encounter like a red thread.
信じて…
I'll believe...
まっすぐ…
straight ahead...
せーので 言葉にして…！
and on three, speak it from the heart!
「キミのヒロインは誰…？」
Who will be your heroine, I wonder...?
きっとキミの心を動かしてみせるよ まだまだぜんぶ足りないけど
I'm sure I can reach your heart and make it beat only for me.
ヒロインオーディション 選んでそして私を いつかギッとしてほしい
Heroine audition, pick me as your choice and hold me close someday.
「ありがとう、ずっと大好きだよ！」
Thank you, I love you so much!
出会った瞬間ってかなりミラクル このチャンスは赤い糸 ギッと手繰り寄せて 運命にしよう
The moment we met was quite a miracle, this chance encounter like a red thread.
信じて…
I'll believe...
まっすぐ…
straight ahead...
せーので 言葉にして…！
and on three, speak it from the heart!
「キミのヒロインは誰…？」
Who will be your heroine, I wonder...?
きっとキミの心を動かしてみせるよ まだまだぜんぶ足りないけど
I'm sure I can reach your heart and make it beat only for me.
ヒロインオーディション 選んでそして私を いつかギッとしてほしい
Heroine audition, pick me as your choice and hold me close someday.
ありがとうずっと 大好きだよ！
Thank you so much, I love you with all my heart!
ありがとう！みんな大好きだよ！
Thank you! I love you all so much!
もう一回だよ！
One more time, hey!
大好き！
I love you!